ALEXANDER MARCELL

WEB DEVELOPER

EXPERIENCE

Real Estate Sales Consultant | Keller Williams

AUG 2015 - 2019, MIAMI, FL

- Consulted and negotiated contract terms and purchase price in order to help clients accomplish their real estate buying, selling or investment goals.
- Professionally marketed services using a multipronged approach including online advertising, video tours and open houses, which led to more efficient sales.
- Guided sellers and buyers through real estate transactions by setting realistic expectations during transactions, leading to greater customer retention and a smoother closing process.

Operation Specialist | Najé Essentials, Inc

MAR 2012 - 2015, MIAMI, FL

- Resolved complex administrative problems, saved valuable time, and increased productivity in the organization.
- Increased company revenue by \$60,000+ yearly after analyzing website and sales processes, comparing processes and trends with those of competitors, and implementing changes that led to increased monthly revenue goals.
- Determined shipping method for product orders using researched methods for saving money on shipping, which led to enabling the company to offer free shipping and increased sales.

PROJECTS

Developer | BandSite Project

FEB 2022, BrainStation/ Project

 Built website utilizing HTML, JAVASCRIPT, SCSS and AXIOS calls to get information from API

Developer | BandSite Project

MAR 2022, BrainStation/Project

Built website utilizing REACT JS, SCSS and AXIOS calls to an API

Co-creator | Dad Jokes App

FEB 2022, BrainStation/HACKATHON

Built with REACT JSX & SCSS where we utilized AXIOS call to dadjokez API

Creator | Solei Cosmetic E-Commerce Website

MAR 2022, CAPSTONE PROJECT

Simple E-commerce site for an online business that takes payments

thealexmarcell@gmail.com 646-667-5247 linkedin.com/in/alex-marcell

github.com/alexandermarcell

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, DOM APIs, Web APIs, User Authentication, OAuth, Heroku, Jira, Figma, GitHub, Jest, React, Node, Knex, MySQL, Flexbox, BEM, GitHub

PROFILE

I am a recent Brainstation web development graduate with a passion for responsive website design and a firm believer in the mobile-first approach. I hope to use my expert problem solving and communication skills to work with teams developing products and tools people love to use.

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma
Candidate, Web
Development

JAN 2022 - APR 2022, NEW YORK, NY

Florida International
University | Bachelors in
Economics, Minor Finance

AUG 2009 - 2014, MIAMI, FL

Broward College | A.A. History

MAY 2008 - 2009, Fort Lauderdale, FL